# ZHACHORY VOLKER

ME@ZHACHORY.COM | (940) 315-4580

I am a Software Engineer with 12+ years of full stack experience, 6+ years in graphic design, and 6+ years of data mining. I am expanding my knowledge toward Machine Learning and Mis-in-formation. I enjoy learning new things every day, and I always give my 100% in everything I do. I aim to become a Researcher in AI/ML in the near future. I would like to focus on Graph Learning and Time Series Analysis for News applications.

# **Education**

University of North Texas Bachelors of Computer Science August 2013 - May 2018 GPA: 3.443

#### Relevant Coursework:

Advanced Algorithms, Data Structures, Software Engineering, Discrete Math, Game Mechanics, Operating Systems, Artificial Intelligence

#### Dean's List:

Fall 2013, Spring 2015, Fall 2015, Spring 2016

# **Skills**

#### Language Concepts

Go, Python, C++, Java,
JavaScript, Web Languages,
Machine Learning, MapReduce,
Full-Stack, Data Analysis,
NLP, OOP, Test-Driven Development,
Genetic Algorithms, Reinforcement Learning, Technical
Stock Analysis

## Systems Soft

Tensorflow, PyTorch, Jupyter, Hadoop, LAMP/MEAN, NodeJS, Group Work, Project Management, Oral Communications, Technical Communications, Quick Learning, Adobe

## Connect

Github: @Zhachory1 LinkedIn: zhachory1 Website: zhach.me Twitter: @MlZhach

# **Experience**

### **Software Engineer** YouTube Search March 2018 - Present | New York, New York

Working on a multi-faceted team. We create features and metrics in Go for ranking systems. We maintain and improve multiple mapreduce pipelines to create aggregated logs that calculate ranking metrics to be used for enhancing users' experience. And we improve the News experience on YouTube Search using clustering algorithms, NLP models, and scalable infrastructure.

Recently saved 60% of resources with a major project. Analyzing metrics to create ranking models. Using deep networks to embed user behaviors and cluster them to improve experimentation.

Recently launched a new feature for YouTube Search to show a news article for queries looking for information about a breaking news event and we don't have any videos about the event. This helps fight against misinformation and helps people get information for breaking news events faster.

### Software Engineering Resident Google

March 2017 - March 2018 | New York, New York

In one research team, worked with Java, TypeScript, and Angular to create a full stack application. Worked with NLP and Machine Learning with Python to attach questions to answers/doc space with Seq2Seq and DSSM. Created and maintained mapreduce pipelines in C++ to maintain the corpus size of our application.

In the another research team, maintained and added features to a library made for graph mining for all of Google to use. Created pipelines to implement label propagation and other semi-supervised learning algorithms for large graphs. Made evaluation functions for library to make training more robust and effective.

#### System Data & Performance Intern Ericsson

May 2015 - March 2017 | Plano, Texas

Monitored systems with the Zabbix monitoring system and take action if anything goes wrong. Developed and maintained full-stack applications and systems to simplify Ericsson's processes and routines in Polymer/other web frameworks and Python/Java. Managed databases with PostgreSQL, MySQL, Cassandra, MongoDB, and HBase for multiple applications across multiple servers. Mined data from these databases to predict site mis-handlements and suggest possible solutions. Managed computer systems with Hadoop, Linux, and Windows. Created internal marketing campaigns with videos, newsletters, and programs.

I feel my work helped Ericsson onto a path of a simplified and energetic work life. A lot dealt with easing the burden for the everyday Ericsson employee and made the workflow inviting and clear.